filipiniana.net 2007-05-02

# FILIPINIANA.NET

Filipiniana.net collects information about

**Personally identifiable information**

Personally identifiable information may be collected in conjunction with necessary processes. This information may include, but are not limited to: (1) First and last name, (2) Address, (3) ZIP/Postal Code, (4) Email address, (5) Telephone number, (6) Affiliated library information, or (7) Credit card numbers and other billing information.

**IP Address**

The FILIPINIANA.NET web site logs IP addresses for system administration purposes. Your IP address can help us diagnose service problems and provide session statistics.

**Cookies**

FILIPINIANA.NET uses a common feature of Web sites known as a cookie to store your member ID and state information about where you are in the site, as well as to track current and past activity. FILIPINIANA.NET does not store any of your personal information in cookies. A cookie is simply a small data file that the Web site writes to your browser. A cookie can't read any other data off your hard drive, pass on a virus, or read cookie files created by other sites. You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser, however, the FILIPINIANA.NET web site's functionality may be affected.

**Registration**

In order to take advantage of some features of the site, you must register and create a member account. A FILIPINIANA.NET online registration form may require you to provide information such as your name, email address, a User Name, and a password.

**Usage and Circulation Records**

Any information collected may be used to analyze usage, evaluate service effectiveness and provide training material, and to facilitate library research.

**Questions, Comments, and Entries to Open Forums and Reviews**

We encourage members to provide personal information ONLY in fields specifically designed for such information such as registration and log-on.  

Comments and entries to forums and reviews are posted in real time. Consequently, your entire submission may appear in an open forum or review. Please be aware that any personal information you include within this entry field will be available to the public.

**Why Information is Collected**

The majority of the information we collect is analyzed so that we can improve your FILIPINIANA.NET experience. This information is not shared outside of FILIPINIANA.NET except as described in this policy. If necessary, we will use your information to contact you. Except as permitted by this policy, FILIPINIANA.NET does not send unsolicited e-mails

The purposes for collecting information and contacting you are:

(1) Registration  
(2) To fulfill requests for FILIPINIANA.NET tools, programs and other future services  
(3) For customer service and support  
(4) To provide information and answering questions related to the use and offered services.  
(5) To provide updates on our sites and other services  
(6) To deliver newsletters  
(7) To notify service expiration dates.  
(8) Facilitating participation in an FILIPINIANA.NET Open Forum or Review  
(9) Compiling aggregate statistical and academic analysis

NOTES: 

(1) Notify Filnet users of ads or, if the purpose involves the use of sensitive information, it will seek your consent to use and disclose personal information for that purpose.

(2) User information will not be used for reasons beyond the scope of the stated purposes and FILIPINIANA.NET will never willfully disclose personally identifiable information to a third party outside of the stated purposes unless:

1\. There is violation of the Terms of Use or another applicable Agreement, or

2\. It is a requirement to do so by law

3\. There is need to notify the user/member.

FILIPINIANA.NET has taken reasonable steps to ensure the protection of your information, and to prevent the loss, misuse, or alteration of that information.

**Third Parties**

At times, FILIPINIANA.NET partners with third parties to complete its stated purposes. In these instances, third parties may require the use of personally identifiable information. For instance, information must be disclosed to process orders through online store, interact with Regional Service Providers, and to market products or services to you. These third-party sites are not covered by this Privacy Statement. These sites may have their own privacy policies or statements and we encourage users to read before providing information.

This web site contains links to other sites. Such links do not imply FILIPINIANA.NET’s endorsement or guarantee of the products, information or recommendations provided by these third party sites.

Please be aware that FILIPINIANA.NET is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our end-users, when they leave our site, to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site.

**Opt-Out Features**

(1) These feature enables a user to tell us that they don’t want to receive communication from FILIPINIANA.NET, such as email, newsletter announcement, new features or content, opt out at registration, or send an email to [webmaster@filipiniana.net](mailto:webmaster@filipiniana.net)

(2) You can decline to provide personal information to us or opt out at anytime. However, this may limit your ability to utilize the services on the web site. 

**Security**

We have put in place reasonable measures to protect the personal information contained in our databases. Measures are in place to prevent unauthorized access and maintain appropriate use and accuracy. Furthermore, data that is transmitted in association with our online store is encrypted and is secured by SSL.

Your password is a component of our security system. As such, it is your responsibility to protect it. Do not share your password with any third parties. If your password has been compromised for any reason, you should change it immediately.

Access to Information

FILIPINIANA.NET provides links in their e-mail communications and web pages for managing the information that is sent. If you have questions about the information collected about yourself, would like to update or make changes to your information, or are concerned that your information is inaccurate or incomplete please contact [webmaster@filipiniana.net](mailto:webmaster@filipiniana.net). We make a reasonable effort to ensure that information contained in our database is accurate and, when necessary, current.  

**Contact and Notice**

From time to time, we may update this privacy policy. We will notify you about material changes in the way we treat personal information by placing notice on our site. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this policy so that you always will know what information we collect, how we use it and to whom we disclose it.

If you have any questions regarding our policies, please contact webmaster@filipiniana.net or write to:

FILIPINIANA.NET  
1253 G. Araneta Avenue, Quezon City  
1104 Philippines
